Finding Aid for Robert J. Harris papers, ca. 1959-ca. 1963 and 1969-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert J. Harris papers circa 1959-1963 and 1969-1973
Harris, Robert J.
43.5 linear feet
851427 Aa 2
Democratic mayor of Ann Arbor, Michigan; University of Michigan law school professor. Papers include mayoralty files relating to city politics and municipal issues, including the affairs of the police department and other city departments, the Ann Arbor Transportation Authority, the Model Cities Program, and the Southeast Michigan Council of Governments (SEMCOG); and scattered law school course and research materials, ca. 1959-ca. 1963
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donor number 5360.
The collection is open to research.
Rober J. Harris was a full-time member of the University of Michigan Law School faculty from 1959-74 and an adjunct professor for many year and served as mayor of Ann Arbor from 1969-1973.
Harris was born Oct. 5, 1930, in Boston. He graduated Phi Beta Kappa from Wesleyan University and was a Rhodes Scholar. At Yale Law School, he was a member of the Law Review and the Order of the Coif, an honorary scholastic society. He served in the Army for two years during the Korean War, and moved in 1959 to Ann Arbor where he served as an attorney, in addition to his service as a law professor and mayor.
Harris's tenure as mayor came during turbulent times. Faced with protests against the Vietnam War, he worked with activists and University and city officials to keep the demonstrations peaceful and the city safe.
Harris served on many community boards and was a founding member of Friends of Legal Aid, which provides support to Legal Services of South Central Michigan. He also did extensive pro bono work for indigent individuals and for numerous groups, including Ozone House, Perry Nursery School and S.O.S. Community Services.
In his retirement, Harris tutored children in reading and volunteered for Food Gatherers. He also had a passion for model airplanes and jazz.
The Robert J. Harris papers document his term as mayor of Ann Arbor, 1979-1983 and a professor at the University of Michigan law School, 1959-1974. Papers include mayoralty files relating to city politics and municipal issues, including the affairs of the police department and other city departments, the Ann Arbor Transportation Authority, the Model Cities Program, and the Southeast Michigan Council of Governments (SEMCOG); and scattered law school course and research materials, ca. 1959-ca. 1963.
The papers are organized into eight series: Alphabetical Files (boxes 1-9); Model Cities; Boards and Commissions File, City Departments File, Council Activities File, Miscellaneous Files, Newspaper clipping File, and Law School.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.). Common Council.; Mayors--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Michigan--Politics and government--1971-1980.; Municipal government--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Police--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Transportation--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Law School.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
- Alphabetical File
  - Abortion Reform (Box 1)
  - Administrative Management Association (Box 1)
  - Agency Shop (Box 1)
  - Aging, Conference on (Box 1)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Architects (Box 1)
  - American Legion (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Area Foundation (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Art Association (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Board of Realtors (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Citizens Council (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Community Center (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Council for the Performing Arts (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Exchange Club (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Independent Housing Inc. (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Ministerial Association (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Public Schools (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Railroad Company Trackage (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Symphony Orchestra (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Township Board (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Tribal Council (Box 1)
  - Annexation Policy (Box 1)
  - Applied Dynamics Company (Box 1)
  - Arbitration, Compulsory (Box 1)
  - Arbor-A, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Arbor Park (Box 1)
  - Arboretum (Box 1)
  - Argus (Box 1)
  - Art Fair (Box 1)
  - Associated Food Dealers (Box 1)
  - Associated Petroleum Industries of Michigan (Box 1)
  - Automobile Club of Michigan Report (Box 1)
  - Bangladesh Relief (Box 1)
  - Barfield Cleaning Company (Box 1)
  - Biafra Support Organizations (Box 1)
  - Billboards (Box 1)
  - Black Action Movement (Box 1)
  - Black Community (Box 1)
  - Black Contractors Association (Box 1)
  - Black People United (Box 1)
  - Blacks United for Liberation and Justice (Box 1)
  - Blues Festival (Box 1)
  - Bomb Craters on Campus (Box 1)
  - Bonding, Municipal (Box 1)
  - Boy Scouts of America (Box 1)
  - Brain Mistrust (Box 1)
  - Briarwood. Shopping Center (Box 1)
  - Burns Park Facility (Box 1)
  - Campership Program-Community Camp (Box 1)
  - Cancer Society (Box 1)
  - CAP, Inc. (Box 1)
  - Census (Box 2)
  - Ceremonials (Box 2)
  - Chamber of Commerce (also Central Business District. (Box 2)
  - and Ann Arbor Tomorrow) (Box 2)
  - Charter Convention (Box 2)
  - Charter Realty (Box 2)
  - Child and Family Services (Box 2)
  - Children's Farm Proposal (Box 2)
  - Citizen's Association for Area Planning (Box 2)
  - Citizens Information Service (Box 2)
  - Clague Middle School (Box 2)
  - Clinton School (Box 2)
  - Coffees (October, 1969) (Box 2)
  - Colonial Square Housing (Box 2)
  - Commission on Professional and Hospital Activities (CPHA) (Box 2)
  - Commission on the Status of Women (Washtenaw County) (Box 2)
  - Committee on Law and Housing (Box 2)
  - Community Center Coordinating (Box 2)
  - Community Coordinated Child Care (Box 2)
  - Complaints (Box 2)
  - Conference of large university town officials (Box 2)
  - Conference of Mayors (U.S.) (Box 2)
  - Conflict of Interest (Box 2)
  - Congratulations on re-election 1971 (Box 2)
  - Congressional-City Conference (Box 2)
  - Conservation Commissions (Box 2)
  - Consortium International (Box 2)
  - Consumer Protection Legislation (Box 2)
  - Cooperative Services, Inc. (Box 2)
  - Copernicus Committee (Box 2)
  - Council Campaign 1970 (Box 2)
  - Council Campaign 1972 (Box 2)
  - Council of Churches (Box 2)
  - Cultural Enrichment Program at St. Francis School (Box 2)
  - Day Camp Proposal (Box 2)
  - Day Care (Box 3)
  - Day Care (Box 3)
  - Democratic Party (Box 3)
  - Detroit Edison (Box 3)
  - Disabled American Veterans (Box 3)
  - Divine Light Mission (Box 3)
  - Dog Control (Box 3)
  - Downtown Business and Development Association (Box 3)
  - Draft Repeal (Box 3)
  - Drug bills introduced in the state legislature (Box 3)
  - Earth Catalog (Box 3)
  - Ecology Center (Box 3)
  - Economic Development Act (Box 3)
  - Eighteen Year Old Vote (Box 3)
  - Emergency Phone #911 (Box 3)
  - Employment (Box 3)
  - Environmental Protection Agency (Box 3)
  - Environmental Protection Legislation (Box 3)
  - Environmental Research Institute (Box 3)
  - Environmental Teach-In (Box 3)
  - Fair Campaign Practice Committee (Box 3)
  - Farah Boycott (Box 3)
  - FASST-Federation of Americans Supporting Science and Technology (Box 3)
  - Federal Regional Council (Box 3)
  - Fisher Cadillac Property (Box 3)
  - Fisheries Lab (Box 3)
  - Flags (Box 3)
  - Flood Insurance (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 3)
  - Forest Avenue Property (Box 3)
  - Galens (Box 3)
  - Gas Tax Legislation 1972 (Box 3)
  - Geddes Pond (Box 4)
  - Gifts (Box 4)
  - Graduate Assembly (Box 4)
  - Great Lakes Basin Commission (Box 4)
  - Project Grow (Community Garden Project) (Box 4)
  - Guild House (Box 4)
  - Halfway House (Proposal of Dennis White) (Box 4)
  - Halloween (Box 4)
  - Health, Education and Welfare (HEW) (Box 4)
  - Health Planning (Box 4)
  - Highway Research Institute (Box 4)
  - Hockey League (Box 4)
  - Honeywell (Box 4)
  - Housing Assistance Administration (Box 4)
  - Housing Bond Referendum (Box 4)
  - Housing-Misc. (Box 4)
  - Housing-Student Papers on Housing in Ann Arbor (Box 4)
  - HUD (Box 4)
  - Human Rights Party (Box 4)
  - HRP Platform, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Huron-Clinton Metropolitan Authority (Box 4)
  - Indian Students Association (Box 4)
  - Insurance (Box 4)
  - Institute of Public Policies Studies (Box 4)
  - Interfaith Council for Peace (Box 4)
  - Intergovernmental Personnel Act (Box 4)
  - Interior Department Contract Compliance Bill (Box 4)
  - International Center (Box 4)
  - International City Management Association (Box 4)
  - International Neighbors (Box 4)
  - Internships (Box 4)
  - Jaycees (Box 4)
  - Judicial Selection-Reform Proposal (Box 5)
  - Junior Achievement (Box 5)
  - Justice Department (U.S) (Box 5)
  - Juvenile Court Officers Association (Box 5)
  - Keep Michigan Beautiful (Box 5)
  - Kentucky Fried Chicken (Box 5)
  - King Elementary School (Box 5)
  - Kiplinger Letter on Population (Box 5)
  - Kiwanis Club (Box 5)
  - Lakewood PTO (Box 5)
  - Landlord-Tenant Collective Bargaining (Box 5)
  - Landlord-Tenant Relations Act (Box 5)
  - Lansky Junkyard (Box 5)
  - Lawyers Committee for Civil Rights under Law (Box 5)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 5)
  - Lettuce Boycott (Box 5)
  - Lions Club (Box 5)
  - Liveability Incorporated (Box 5)
  - Mack School (Box 5)
  - Manpower Training and, Employment (Box 5)
  - Maple Hills Cooperative (Box 5)
  - Maple Village Shopping Center (Box 5)
  - March of Dimes (Box 5)
  - Marijuana Ordinance (Box 5)
  - Mark's Coffee House (Box 5)
  - Mayor's Exchange Day (Box 5)
  - McGovern Campaign (Box 5)
  - Metropolitan Fund, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Michigan-re: State and local budgets (Box 6)
  - Michigan Attorney General's Office (Box 6)
  - Michigan Bell Telephone Company (Box 6)
  - Michigan Civil Rights Committee (Box 6)
  - Michigan Committee on Law Enforcement and Criminal Justice (Box 6)
  - Michigan Daily (Box 6)
  - Michigan Emergency Committee Against the Housing Cut-Off (Box 6)
  - Michigan Legislature (Box 6)
  - Michigan Municipal League (Box 6)
  - Michigan Partners of the Alliance (Box 6)
  - Michigan, State of (Misc. Departments) (Box 6)
  - Michigan State Boundary Commission (Box 6)
  - Michigan. State Department of Commerce (Box 6)
  - Michigan. State Department of Highway Construction (Box 6)
  - Michigan. State Housing Development Authority (Box 6)
  - Michigan. Insurance Commission (Box 6)
  - Michigan. Public Service Commission (Box 6)
  - Michigan Department of Natural Resources (Box 6)
  - Michigan State Police (Box 6)
  - Michigan Water Resources Commission (Box 6)
  - Michigan Week (Box 6)
  - Mill Creek Park (Box 6)
  - Miss Michigan 1970 (Box 6)
  - Muscular Dystrophy Association (Box 7)
  - Muskegon Seaway Festival (Box 7)
  - Narcotics Addiction Rehabilitation Coordinating Organization (Box 7)
  - National Alliance of Businessmen (Box 7)
  - National Committee for an Effective Congress (Box 7)
  - National Federation of Independent Business (Box 7)
  - National League of Cities (Box 7)
  - Navy Department (Box 7)
  - Negro History Week (Box 7)
  - New Detroit (Box 7)
  - Newport School (Box 7)
  - New Understandings Committee (Box 7)
  - No Fault Insurance-Cabs, Autos, Buses (Box 7)
  - North Central Property Owners Association (Box 7)
  - Northeast Area Planning Review Committee (Box 7)
  - Northern Ireland (Box 7)
  - Northern Michigan University (Box 7)
  - Octagon House (Box 7)
  - Open Office Hours (Box 7)
  - Office Hours--Follow-up Activity (Box 7)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 7)
  - Office Management & Budget (Box 7)
  - Ohio State Football Game (Box 7)
  - Old West Side Association (Box 7)
  - Operation Breakthrough (Housing) (Box 7)
  - Optimists (Box 7)
  - Orthopsychiatry Conference (Box 7)
  - Our Own Thing (Box 7)
  - Outdoor Cafes (Box 7)
  - Owens-Illinois Glass Company (Box 7)
  - Parental Responsibility (Box 7)
  - Parents In Support of Students (Box 7)
  - Peace Rally, Petitions and Related Activities (Box 7)
  - Penn Central Railroad (Box 7)
  - People to People
    - General Carl Zwinch (Box 7)
    - Tubingen, Germany 1971 (Box 7)
    - Tubingen, Germany (Box 7)
    - Hikone, Japan (Box 7)
    - Belije City, British Honduras (Box 7)
  - Pittsfield Township (Box 7)
  - Pittsfield Village (Box 7)
  - Pointe Mouille (Box 7)
  - Polk (R.L.) & Co. (Box 7)
  - Pontiac Heights Cooperative (Box 7)
  - Post Office (Box 7)
  - Postal Clerks (Box 7)
  - Precinct Delegate Election (Box 7)
  - Preferential Voting (Box 7)
  - Prison Labor Unions (Box 7)
  - Prisoner of War Committee (Box 7)
  - PIRGIM (Box 7)
  - Purple Heart Order (Box 7)
  - Press Releases (Box 7)
  - Proclamations January 1972 (Box 7)
  - Proclamations- August 1971-December 1971 (Box 7)
  - Proclamations- July 1970-July 1971 (Box 7)
  - Radical Independent Party (Box 7)
  - Radio Stations-WAAM, WPAG, WUOM (Box 7)
  - Reapportionment (Box 7)
  - Recall campaign (Box 7)
  - Red Cross (Box 7)
  - Rent Freeze (Box 7)
  - Republican Party (Box 7)
  - Rotary Club (Box 7)
  - St. Joseph Mercy Hospital (Box 8)
  - Salvation Army (Box 8)
  - School Bussing-Correspondence (Box 8)
  - Win Schulers (Box 8)
  - Scio Township (Box 8)
  - Senior Citizens Guild (Box 8)
  - Senior Citizens Program Recreation Department (Box 8)
  - Senior Citizens Youth Volunteer Programs (Box 8)
  - Sex Discrimination in Schools (Box 8)
  - Sheriff (Box 8)
  - Sierra Club (Box 8)
  - Sinclair (John) Committee to Free (Box 8)
  - Sister Lake Conservation Association (Box 8)
  - Slauson Jr. High School (Box 8)
  - Bert L. Smokler Co. (Box 8)
  - Solicitation Permit Guidelines (Box 8)
  - Southeast Michigan Tourist Association (Box 8)
  - Southeast Regional Criminal Justice Training Center (Box 8)
  - Southeastern Michigan Transportation Authority (SEMTA) (Box 8)
  - Speeches-1972 (Box 8)
  - Speeches- 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Speech to New Detroit (Box 8)
  - Speeches not used (Box 8)
  - Speech-Budget Message (Box 8)
  - Special Olympics for Handicapped 1972 (Box 8)
  - State Street Area Association (Box 8)
  - Student Government Council (Box 8)
  - Student Organizations (Box 8)
  - Student Voting (Box 8)
  - Superior Township (Box 8)
  - Tax Reform (Box 9)
  - Teen Center (Box 9)
  - Tenants Rights Legislation at State Level (Box 9)
  - Tenants Rights Booklet (Box 9)
  - Tenants Union (Box 9)
  - Thank Yous (Box 9)
  - Transpo-1972 (Box 9)
  - Unitarian Congress Committee of America (Box 9)
  - Unemployment Compensation (Box 9)
  - Unions (Box 9)
  - Unions-Re Davis Bacon Act (Box 9)
  - United Black Council for Resource Development (Box 9)
  - United Fund (Box 9)
  - United Nations Day-1971 & 1972 (Box 9)
  - United Nations Day-1970 (Box 9)
  - United Nations. Day-1969 (Box 9)
  - U.S. Department of Transportation (Box 9)
  - U.S. Treasury-Internal Revenue Service (Box 9)
  - U/M Misc. (Box 9)
  - U/M Central Campus Concept (Box 9)
  - U/M Homecoming (Box 9)
  - U/M Housing (Box 9)
  - University Relations (Box 9)
  - University Towers (Box 9)
  - Urban Coalition-Umbrella Organization (Box 9)
  - Urban Proposals for Coalition (Box 9)
  - Urban Demonstration Program (Box 9)
  - Urban Information Systems (Box 9)
  - Urban Law Institute (Box 9)
  - Urban Vehicle Design Competition (Box 9)
  - Urbanarium. (Box 9)
  - Veterans Affairs (Box 9)
  - Veterans Cab (Box 9)
  - Vietnam War-Misc. (Box 9)
  - Vista (Box 9)
  - Vocational Education (Box 9)
  - Vocational Residential Center (Box 9)
  - Voting Rights Bill-Federal (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw Association for Retarded Children (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw Community College (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw Contractors Association (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw Council on Aging (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County-Misc. (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Board of Commissioners and Supervisors (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Community Mental Health Center (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Committee for Economic Opportunity (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Council on Alcoholism (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Department of Public Works (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Drain Commission (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Health Department (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Hospital (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Jail (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Law Enforcement & Justice Planning Board (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Overall Economic Development Plan (OEDP) (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Planning Commission (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Public Defender Program (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Road Commission (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Soil Conservation (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Youth Services (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw Environmental Council (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw Intermediate School District (Box 10)
  - Washtenaw Neighborhood Group (Box 10)
  - Water Supply (Box 10)
  - Welcome Wagon (Box 10)
  - West Stadium Business & Professional Association (Box 10)
  - Westgate Shopping Center (Box 10)
  - While Panther Party (Box 10)
  - Yellow & Checker Cab Company (Box 10)
  - YM-YWCA (Box 10)
  - Youth (Box 10)
  - Youth-Mayor's Ad Hoc Committee on (Box 10)
  - Youth-Possible Funding Sources on Juvenile Activities (Box 10)
  - Youth Advisory Committee (Box 10)
  - Youth & Juvenile Advisory Committee (Box 10)
  - Youth Commission (Box 10)
  - Youth Consortium (Box 10)
  - Youth & Delinquency (Box 10)
  - Youth Employment (Box 10)
  - Youth Needs-Faber Ad hoc Committee on (Box 10)
  - Youth-Blue Ribbon Committee on Juvenile Offenders (Box 10)
  - Youth-Ozone House (Box 10)
  - Youth-Summer 1970 Programs (Box 10)
  - Youth for Understanding (Box 10)
  - Ypsilanti Township (Box 10)
- Model Cities
  - Model Cities File (Box 10)
  - Model Cities File (Box 11)
    (continued)
  - Model Cities File (Box 12)
- Boards and Commissions File
  - Appointments (Box 12)
  - Building Code Advisory Board (Box 12)
  - Board of Canvassers (Box 12)
  - Board of Examiners of Electricians and Electrical Contractors (Box 12)
  - Board of Examiners--Heating Code (Box 12)
  - Board of Health (Box 12)
  - Board of Insurance Administration (Box 13)
  - Pension and Retirement Board (Box 13)
  - Plumbing Advisory Board (Box 13)
  - Citizens Recreation Board (Box 13)
  - Recreation Programs-Sex Discrimination (Box 13)
  - Board of Review (Box 13)
  - Taxicab board (Box 13)
  - Underground Utilities Advisory Board (Box 13)
  - Underground Wiring Board (Box 13)
  - Building Board of Appeals (Box 13)
  - Housing Board of Appeals (Box 13)
  - Sign Board of Appeals (Box 13)
  - Zoning Board of Appeals (Box 13)
  - Boundary Commission (Box 13)
  - CATV Commission (Cable Antenna Television) (Box 13)
  - Economic Development and Manpower Commission (Box 14)
  - Historical Commission (Box 14)
  - Housing Commission (Box 14)
  - Human Relations Commission (Box 14)
  - Human Rights Commission (Box 14)
  - Human Rights Commission (Box 15)
  - City Market Commission (Box 15)
  - Planning Commission (Box 15)
  - Rent Control Commission (Box 15)
  - Sesquicentennial Commission (Box 15)
  - Airport Advisory Committee (Box 15)
  - Arts Committee (Box 15)
  - Beautification Committee (Box 15)
  - Bicycle Coordinating Committee (Box 15)
  - Citizens Blue Ribbon Committee on Drug Abuse (Box 15)
  - Citizens Blue Ribbon Committee on Drug Abuse (Box 16)
  - Expediting Committee (Box 16)
  - Ad Hoc Goals Committee (Box 16)
  - Growth Committee (Box 16)
  - Problems of the Handicapped Committee (Box 16)
  - Host Committee (Box 16)
  - Natural Resources Citizen Advisory Committee (Box 16)
  - Police Community Relations Committee (Box 16)
  - Runaway Committee (Box 16)
  - Citizens Committee on Third Parties (Box 16)
  - City Safety Committee (Box 16)
  - Citizens Tax Committee (Box 16)
  - Workable Program Committee (Box 16)
  - Ann Arbor Building Authority (Box 16)
  - Transportation Authority Appointments (Box 16)
  - Ann Arbor Transit Authority (including Dial-A-Ride) (Box 16)
  - Ancillary Manpower Planning Board (Box 17)
  - Institute on Community Relations (Box 17)
  - Huron River Watershed Council (Box 17)
  - Ann Arbor Citizens Safety and Traffic Council (Box 17)
  - Women's Commission (Box 17)
- City Departments File
  - Administrator (Box 17)
  - Airport (Box 17)
  - Assessor (Box 17)
  - Attorney (Box 17)
  - Building and Safety (Box 17)
  - Building and Safety (Box 18)
  - Central Services (Box 18)
  - Civil Defense (Box 18)
  - Clerk (Box 18)
  - Community Renewal Program (Box 18)
  - Controller (Box 18)
  - District Court (Box 18)
  - Fire (Box 18)
  - Grievance Officer (Box 19)
  - Human Rights (Box 19)
  - Information Bureau (Box 19)
  - Mayor (Box 19)
  - Parks and Recreation (Box 19)
  - Personnel (Box 20)
  - Planning (Box 20)
  - Police (Box 20)
  - Police (Box 21)
  - Public Works (Box 21)
  - Public Works (Box 22)
  - Purchasing (Box 22)
- Council Activities File
  - Council Committees (Box 23)
  - Council-Misc. (Box 23)
  - Agendas (Box 23)
  - Administrators Communications to Council (Box 23)
  - Annexations (Box 23)
  - Legislation
    - Abandoned Automobiles (Box 24)
    - Aerial Advertising (Box 24)
    - Caberet & Dance Hall (Box 24)
    - Consumer Protection (Box 24)
    - Curfew (Box 24)
    - Damage deposits (Box 24)
    - Dishonored checks (Box 24)
    - Disorderly conduct (obscenity) (Box 24)
    - Drive-ins (Box 24)
    - Fireworks (Box 24)
    - Gun control (Box 24)
    - Haller (Martin) Alley (Box 24)
    - Handicap Ordinance (Box 24)
    - Health (Box 24)
    - Historical preservation (Box 24)
    - Housing code (Box 24)
    - Human rights ordinance (Box 24)
    - Impoundment-of vehicles (Box 24)
    - Inspection fees (Box 24)
    - Landscape & Land use (Box 24)
    - Lawn extension (Box 24)
    - Liquor licenses (Box 24)
    - Manhole ordinance (Box 24)
    - Meat market regulations (Box 24)
    - Noise ordinance (Box 24)
    - Nutritional Content labeling (Box 24)
    - Open dating (Box 24)
    - Packard Road widening (Box 24)
    - Parking (Box 24)
    - Phosphates (Box 24)
    - Planned Unit development ordinance (PUD) (Box 24)
    - Pollution (Air) (Box 24)
    - Safety glazing materials (Box 24)
    - School bus stopping ordinance (Box 24)
    - School crossing guard ordinance (Box 24)
    - Sidewalk assessment procedures (Box 24)
    - Site plan actions (Box 24)
    - Soil erosion and sediment control (Box 24)
    - Star Bar entertainment permit (Box 24)
    - Strikebreakers ordinance (Box 24)
    - Subdivision and land use control (Box 25)
    - Train whistles (Box 25)
    - Transient traders (Box 25)
    - Underground wiring (Box 25)
    - Unit pricing (Box 25)
    - User charges (Box 25)
    - Zoning matters (Box 25)
  - Revenue and budget files
    - Revenue Sharing File (Box 25)
    - Revenue Sharing File (Box 26)
    - City Income Tax Campaigns 1969 & 1972 (Box 26)
    - City Budget File (Box 27)
    - City Budget File (Box 28)
- Miscellaneous Files
  - Regional Police proposal (Box 29)
  - Southeast Michigan Council of Governments (SEMCOG) File (Box 29)
  - South Michigan Council of Governments (SEMCOG) File (Box 30)
  - Police department reports & statistics (Box 30)
  - Black action movement police report (Box 30)
  - Police contract negotiations (Box 31)
  - Community Police proposals (Box 31)
  - City Employee contract (Box 31)
  - Briar wood Shopping Center (Box 31)
  - National League of Cities (Box 32)
  - U.S. Conference of Mayors (Box 32)
  - Washtenaw County Board of Public Works (Box 32)
  - Huron River Watershed Council (Box 32)
  - Cooperative area manpower planning system (Box 32)
  - Ann Arbor Area Foundation (Box 32)
  - Zoning actions (Box 32)
  - Street construction (Box 33)
  - Packard-Beakes (Ashley-First) Project (Box 33)
  - Forest-Observatory project (Box 33)
  - Site plans (Box 33)
  - Newport Ridge-Bird Hills project (Box 33)
  - Appointment calendars (Box 33)
- Newspaper clipping File
  - Abandoned Automobiles (Box 34)
  - Administrator (Box 34)
  - Affirmative Action (Box 34)
  - Airport (Box 34)